Wow, what a great view.
哇 风景真不错
I'm delighted.
好开心
Right. Let's post this photo on Instagram.
对了 拍张照片上传到照片墙吧
There we go.
来吧
Hey!
嘿！
-Huh?
怎么了？
I'm in that photo, right? Don't upload it.
拍到我了吧？请不要上传
Huh? But your face isn't in the photo.
什么？可是又没拍到你的脸
Still, some people can tell that it's me.
即使是背影 认识的人还是看得出来
It's an infringement on portrait rights.
这样侵害了肖像权
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
You're the one violating freedom of expression.
你才是侵犯言论自由
-What?
-什么？
Mr. Kayama needs your help with a case.
香山叔叔说一定要委托您处理
Oh, really? I'm sorry.
是吗？真抱歉
If it's urgent, could you ask Haneo to take over?
如果很急的话 可以请羽男接手吗？
I'm giving a consultation on inheritance right now.
有人正在找我咨询继承问题
Oh, okay.
我知道了
Please make sure to charge for that consultation.
您那边的咨询请务必要收取费用
-Come on, he's a friend. -Dad.
-不…他是朋友啊 -爸爸
Since I can't take his request, could you give Kayama an apology discount?
香山的案子我没办法亲自接 你就算他便宜一点吧？
I cannot do that.
不可以这样
Hey, hello? Hello?
喂？
-Huh? Hello? Is it a bad connection? -Dad?
-喂？网络不好吗？ -爸爸？
-Hello?
-喂？
Okay.
好吧
Geez…
真是的…
Yeah, of course I'll pay the regular fee.
当然的啦 照一般价钱就可以了
Oh, really?
真的吗？
I'm in the service business too. I understand the importance of profit.
我也是做服务业 知道营利有多重要
Thank you.
不好意思
Plus, I'm happy to have him work on my case.
而且让他来处理 我也很高兴
Wataro told me that you're a great lawyer.
我听棉郎哥说 你是很厉害的律师
Thank you. Give him a discount.
谢谢 算他便宜一点
Don't make unnecessary remarks.
你不要多嘴
So, what's the request about?
那么 您要委托的内容是什么？
Well…
这个嘛…
My restaurant is on a restaurant guide website.
我的店被放上美食网了
-What? -Was it slandered?
-什么？ -是受到诽谤中伤了吗？
No, it was a good review.
不 是好评
And that's bad?
这有什么不好？
The selling point of his restaurant is that it's a hidden gem.
香山叔叔的店是以信息完全保密的 秘密店家为卖点
Now, let me confirm.
那么 请让我先确认一下
Seven days ago, when you were serving your regular customers
七天前 香山先生 在自己经营的创作料理餐厅
at your creative cuisine restaurant called Inside,
“Inside”里招待常客
a group of unknown customers came in.
一群陌生客人突然进到店里来
They said they saw the review on Umarepo, a restaurant guide website.
一问之下才知道他们是看了 美食网站“美味报报”的评论
The person who posted it was a popular reviewer
发文者是很受欢迎的评论者
who goes by the handle "Refill Master."
笔名叫“再来一碗名人”
You immediately sent a removal request to DotM,
你立刻向经营“美味报报”的 DotM公司
the company that runs Umarepo, but they declined.
申请删文 对方却说办不到
At this rate, your restaurant will lose its stance as a hidden gem,
这样下去将无法维持秘密店家的立场
so you want to sue DotM.
所以想要起诉DotM
-Correct? -Yes.
-对吗？ -对
I've been declining interviews for 15 years and this happens.
这15年来我拒绝了所有的采访 现在却发生这种事
You've never been interviewed once?
你以前从来没有接受过采访吗？
No, never. I've kept my stance on that.
从来没有 这点我很坚持
You're not suing Refill Master?
你要提告的对象 不是“再来一碗名人”吗？
I'm upset about the review too,
我对那个人也很气
but I'm more angry at the company for rejecting my removal request.
但主要是气公司拒绝我删文的请求
I want to demand compensation too.
我也想要求他们赔偿
Very well.
我知道了
Haneoka will handle all communication with them from now on.
今后 与对方的交涉 就交给羽根冈律师
Do you have their contact information?
请问你有对方的联络方式吗？
Yeah, sure. Hang on.
有 等我一下
This is their lawyer.
这位就是对方的律师
FUMIHIKO TANZAWA
（丹泽文彦）
Inside has strictly maintained its referral system style
Inside一直坚持 推介式经营风格
and strived to keep the restaurant private.
努力维护餐厅的神秘感
However, this post has undermined the unique value of the restaurant
不过这次的发文破坏了老板为餐厅
that the owner has built up.
建立起来的独特价值
This is an infringement of goodwill.
这构成了损害商誉
We'd like you to delete the restaurant information and pay--
我方要求立刻删除餐厅信息 并请求赔偿…
Look, Mr. Haneoka.
听好了 羽根冈律师
The Umarepo reviewers have the right to freedom of expression
“美味报报”的发文者有言论自由
and the viewers have the right to know. Therefore…
阅览的用户也有知的权利 因此…
we can't comply with your request to delete the post
我方无法同意删文的要求
and we believe it doesn't constitute an infringement of goodwill.
也认为这并没有构成损害商誉
Our client is happy to take this to court.
我方委托人不排除提告
Go ahead.
请便…
I'll see you there.
我们在法庭上见吧
Do you think I should've grinned wider back there?
刚刚的笑容 我的嘴角是不是高一点比较好？
What? Who cares.
什么？谁管你啊
I can't lose if he's the opponent.
对手是那家伙的话 就不能输
-You shouldn't lose any case. -I know.
-任何案子都不能输 -我知道啦
Then, shall we talk to the regular customers?
我们去找常客谈一谈吧？
We'll get their testimonies on how they love it as a hidden gem.
搜集他们有多喜欢 这里是秘密店家的证词
Maybe this side was better.
或许这边高一点比较好
Good evening.
你们好
Everyone is referred to by regulars
大家若不是由常客介绍
or are the manager's friends, so we do feel at home here.
就是跟老板认识 在这里真的觉得很自在
That's right.
没错…
And what's great is that the manager can improvise dishes on the spot
而且老板还会根据 我们当天的身体状况
according to our physical condition on that day.
即兴做料理给我们吃 这也是一大魅力呢
I think that's possible because he knows us well.
我觉得这是面对常客 才可能提供的服务
That's what I'm most particular about.
那也是我最大的坚持
I want to offer the best thing for them at that moment.
我想为每个人提供 当下最适合他的料理
It really is a great restaurant.
这家餐厅真的很棒
He took half off the bill on our wedding anniversary.
结婚纪念日还会给我们打半价
-That's right! -Truly a great service.
-没错… -服务真的很好
Now, now.
还好啦
So if this place wasn't hidden and strangers frequently visited,
也就是说 如果不再是 陌生人不会来的秘密店家
you think it'll lose its charm.
这里就会失去它的魅力
Yes.
对
Will you testify that in court?
各位愿意上法庭作证吗？
-Of course. -I'm sorry.
-好 -很抱歉
I can't make any promises because my work schedule is unsteady.
我的工作行程比较不稳定 没办法保证一定能去
-Sorry about that. -No worries.
-对不起 -没关系
See you.
那我先走了
-I'm off. -Thank you.
-先走了 -谢谢你
-Bye. -No charge today.
-我回去了 -今天不用钱啦
-Thanks. -Sure.
-谢谢 -没问题
-Take care. -I will.
-路上小心 -好
Are they regular customers in that photo?
这张照片里都是常客吗？
It was our tenth anniversary.
这家餐厅十周年的时候拍的
Most are regulars.
大部分是常客
But this is Mr. Kayama's late wife, Akie.
这位是香山先生过世的太太 明惠小姐
This is his son Hiroshi, and Hiroshi's wife, Ran.
这是他儿子小洋和媳妇小兰
Will they be able to testify?
可以请你儿子媳妇出庭作证吗？
-Probably not. They're overseas, right? -Yeah…
-外派到国外了 应该是没办法吧 -是啊
Oh, if you need testimonies, what about Satsuki?
如果要人作证的话 沙月呢？
-That's it! -Satsuki?
-就是她 -沙月？
She used to work part-time here.
她曾经在这里打工过很长一段时间
Her.
就是她
She'd be perfect.
找沙月很合适
She loves this restaurant and she even found good suppliers for me.
她很爱这家餐厅 甚至帮我找到了不错的食材供货商
Will you ask her?
可以请你们去拜托她吗？
-Sure. -Yes.
-我知道了 -好
Alright.
到了
She said she'd be working here, so we can talk to her anytime.
她说她在这边工作 随时可以来找她
She runs a coffee shop?
她是开咖啡厅的吗？
No, she's a digital nomad.
不是 听说是游牧工作族
Huh? What did you say?
什么？你刚说什么？
D-Digital moped?
邮务工作族？
Digicam comrade?
有无供桌族？
No.
不是
Miracle notepad?
有屋阶级族？
Mythical crawdad?
有子万事足？
-I'll let you continue. -Stop me.
-就看你怎么接下去 -阻止我啊
Don't you know digital nomads?
你不知道游牧工作族吗？
Yeah sure, digital nomads.
我知道啊 游牧工作族嘛
-You know? -I do. They work from different places.
-真的知道吗？ -知道啊 就是到不同地方工作的人
Correct.
答对了
You're that surprised?
有必要那么惊讶吗？
What's going on here?
到底是怎样啦？
How long did you work at Inside?
你在Inside工作了多久？
Ten years, I think.
大概十年吧
How did you start working there?
一开始怎么会在那里打工？
I've been trying to become a writer since back then,
当时我就一直想要当作家
but I couldn't make ends meet.
但是养不活自己
Then the manager's son's wife introduced me.
是老板的儿媳妇介绍我过去的
You mean, Ran?
兰小姐吗？
Yes, we went to the same university.
对 我们念同一所大学
I see.
这样啊
Well, actually…
其实呢…
Someone posted the restaurant's information on Umarepo.
有人在“美味报报”网站 张贴了那家餐厅的信息
This is it. Do you know about this?
就是这个 你知道吗？
Ah, I'm the one who posted this.
这是我张贴的
-What? -Huh?
-咦？ -什么？
You're Refill Master?
你就是“再来一碗名人”？
Yes. I write restaurant reviews as a hobby.
对 我的兴趣是撰写餐厅评论
What? But you shouldn't write about Inside.
什么？Inside不能写吧？
You know it's a hidden restaurant, right?
你知道那是秘密店家吧？
When I post restaurants that other people don't know about, I get more viewers.
张贴出别人不知道的餐厅 点阅率就会增加
I guess it's what you call seeking approval.
就是想要获得认同嘛
Um, what you did could constitute as obstruction of business.
你的行为可能会构成侵害营业秘密罪
Could you delete this?
可以请你删文吗？
I'll consider it if Umarepo told me to,
如果“美味报报”要求的话 我会考虑
but I think it's fine as it is.
但我觉得现在这样很好啊
-You're mad at the restaurant? -No.
-你跟那家餐厅有仇吗？ -没有
What about his son and his wife?
那跟老板的儿子和媳妇呢？
Nope. I see Ran from time to time.
也没有 我偶尔还会跟兰见面
Huh? You go overseas?
什么？到国外吗？
Overseas?
国外？
-Huh?
-什么？
Really? It was Satsuki?
真的吗？是沙月吗？
-Unfortunately. -What?
-真是遗憾 -什么？
She told us that your son and his wife live in Tokyo.
听她说令郎夫妻就住在东京
Why did you lie?
为什么要说谎？
Hiroshi and I had a huge fight three years ago.
大概三年前 我跟洋大吵了一架
I told him never to come back to this restaurant.
我叫他不准再踏进这家餐厅
I didn't want my regulars to know, so I told them they went overseas.
也不知道要怎么跟常客提 只好说他们派驻到国外了
You haven't seen him?
你们没再见面了吗？
Not since the fight.
吵架之后就没有了
Would it be possible for me to meet them?
我可以去见他们吗？
He's watched you work since he was little.
他从小就看着你工作
If he can talk about Inside and you at the trial, it'll help us.
如果能提供关于你和餐厅的证词 对法官的心证也会有帮助
I'm not sure.
我不确定
Maybe it's for the best.
或许那样比较好
Um, you and Mr. Kayama have grown apart?
你跟香山先生好像疏远了？
I guess.
对
If you don't mind…
如果不介意的话…
Oh, the reason?
理由吗？
-Yes.
-对
My dad quit his job when he was 45 and he started that restaurant.
我爸在45岁的时候辞去工作 开了那家餐厅
He barely made a profit since there weren't many customers to begin with
原本客人就不多 他又一直提供折扣
and he kept giving discounts, so my mom worked to support us.
几乎赚不到钱的情况下 是我妈出去工作才撑下去的
I grew up seeing that, so I got a scholarship to a university
我从小看到这样的情况 就去申请了奖学金念大学
and got a stable job.
也找到了稳定的工作
I see. Was that partly as a protest to your father?
原来如此 有点像是对令尊的抗议？
You could say that.
大概吧
When I started working, I realized again
出社会工作之后 我再次体认到
that my dad was doing this with no regard for profit.
我爸做生意完全没有在管获利
He'll lose the restaurant like this.
再这样下去 餐厅迟早会倒闭
That's why you fought?
所以你们才大吵一架？
No. I still didn't say anything.
不 即使这样我还是没说什么
But mom passed away three years ago.
不过3年前 我妈过世了
About the restaurant.
那家餐厅
Hm?
嗯？
Can you go on like this?
照这样的做法撑得下去吗？
You should think about business.
你好好想一下经营方式吧
Even if you give discounts,
再怎么提供服务
it's not like the regulars will take care of you when you retire.
等你退休 常客也不可能来照顾你
It'll only taper off if you only rely on your regulars.
只靠常客光顾 生意也会越做越小
I'm running it my way--
那家餐厅就照我的方式…
You don't get it even after mom sacrificed herself?
连妈都牺牲了 你还不懂吗？
She practically wore her life out for you.
她会这么早死都是爸害的
Do you really mean that?
你说这话是认真的吗？
At this rate, you'll lose the restaurant.
入不敷出 餐厅迟早会倒的
Shut up!
闭嘴
And since then…
事情就是这样…
Even so, the restaurant is in trouble.
不过餐厅现在遇到危机了
Could you please testify?
可以请你出庭作证吗？
No. I'm all for disclosing information about the restaurant.
不 我是赞成公开餐厅信息的
I see…
这样啊…
I wonder why Mr. Kayama is so hung up on keeping his store hidden.
香山叔叔为什么那么坚持 秘密店家的经营方式呢？
I don't know.
我也不知道
He should know that the restaurant will suffer if he disregards profitability.
香山叔叔应该很清楚 不管获利 餐厅迟早会倒的
So why wouldn't he listen to Hiroshi's advice?
为什么不听洋先生的建议呢？
Well, let's try and understand Kayama's feelings too.
你们也体谅一下香山老弟的心情嘛
I get that he wants to put his customers first.
我懂他顾客至上的想法
Doing something for someone is a wonderful gesture.
想为他人付出是很棒的想法
But is it okay to make other people suffer in order to help someone?
但是为了帮助某些人 就可以让其他一些人受苦吗？
You're okay with offering someone an umbrella
为被雨淋得湿透的人撑伞
while getting someone else wet?
害其他人淋雨也没关系吗？
No, that's not what I mean.
我不是那个意思
Mom was soaking wet, while you were busy offering your umbrella to someone else.
在爸爸忙着为其他人撑伞的时候 妈妈一直被雨淋得全身湿透啊
Do you want Aonori seaweed on this?
要加青海苔粉吗？
You came to ask me that?
你就是来问我这件事吗？
No. I just thought you might be hungry.
不 我只是想你可能饿了
Ah, do you prefer bonito flakes over Aonori seaweed?
还是说你不喜欢青海苔 比较喜欢柴鱼片？
I'll leave it here.
我放在这边
I'm sorry.
不好意思
For making you worry.
让你担心了
It's fine.
没有啊
Though I said that,
虽然我那样说
I broke my own rule the other day.
自己上次也打破了原则
I know I have no right to blame my father.
我也知道自己没资格责备我爸
But…
但是…
when I think about my mom…
一想到我妈…
What was your mother like?
你妈妈是什么样的人？
Well, she was gentle and she'd put others before herself.
个性很稳重 总是以别人的事情为优先
That's your father.
那不就是所长嘛
Yes, they might've been alike.
这么说来他们确实很像
She was working here as a clerk.
她一直在这里当职员
Even when my father took on unprofitable requests,
即使我爸无视获利 承接了委托
she would work elsewhere and supported us financially.
我妈也会到外面工作 想办法补贴开支
But she couldn't go on like that, and they got divorced.
不过最后她还是撑不下去 就离婚了
Well, I wouldn't blame her.
也是可以理解啦
I've watched my dad work and I do respect him.
我看着爸爸工作的背影 在心里是尊敬他的
But…
只是…
I also can't get over the feeling that he made my mom suffer.
我一直没办法原谅他害妈受这么多苦
Hence, the politeness?
所以才对他讲敬语吗？
I don't get it myself either.
我也不清楚
He wants you to be more casual.
所长很希望你别再跟他说敬语了
Hm?
嗯？
Nah, not yet.
还不行
So?
怎么样？
Please let me think about it. I can't be casual--
就说了还要再想一想 不说敬语的事…
-You want Aonori seaweed? -That?
-要加青海苔粉吗？ -什么？
Yes.
要
Hey! That's too much!
等一下 加太多了！
It's rich in nutrients.
青海苔营养丰富啊
Is that right? Thank you very much.
那还真是谢谢你了
Here you go.
请享用
You put so much on it…
也加太多了吧
Thank you very much.
谢谢你
Can I talk about the case?
可以聊工作的事吗？
Yes, sure.
请说
The client wants to protect the restaurant's privacy.
委托人希望能保持 秘密店家的经营方式
Putting aside whether we agree with him or not,
先不管我们赞不赞成
let's do whatever we can for him.
我们就竭尽所能帮助他达成期望吧
Of course.
当然好
First, I'll figure out their strategy on preparation day.
首先 在准备期日的确认 就看看对方会怎么出招吧
ARGUMENT PREPARATION DAY
（答辩准备期日）
Does the defense have any additional evidence?
被告方有要追加的证据吗？
Yes. I'll be calling a witness.
有 我们会传唤证人
This is Ms. Fumi Kusakabe.
这位日下部富美小姐
She publishes town magazines in Kamogaya.
出版了鸭谷地区情报志
She did an interview with Inside and posted the article 15 years ago.
15年前曾采访Inside 并发表文章
No way.
不…
Not possible. I've confirmed he's never done an interview.
不可能 我已经确认过 他没有接受过任何采访
Please take a look.
请看
I'll also submit this magazine as evidence at our next hearing.
下次开庭时 我也会提出这份地区情报志做为证据
This means Inside has done an interview in the past
换句话说 Inside过去曾经接受过采访
disclosing its own information.
主动传播了店家信息
So he hasn't exactly maintained strict confidentiality.
并不能说有彻底保密
Additionally, the information posted on Umarepo is
而且在“美味报报”上刊登的信息
pretty much the same as this magazine.
跟这份情报志上面的信息差异不大
We'll be arguing that publishing information
只是让已经公开的信息
which has already been published doesn't constitute an infringement of goodwill.
再次公开而已 我方准备主张这并不构成损害商誉
I'm off to a meeting for the real estate investment fraud case.
我要去开不动产投资诈欺的会了
Please travel safely.
请小心慢走
Hello.
喂
This is really bad!
糟糕了…
-Huh? -Find Mr. Kayama. Right now!
-什么？ -快点找出香山先生在哪里
What's going on? You said you never did an interview!
这是怎么回事？ 你不是说从来没接受过采访！
I completely forgot. This is so embarrassing.
我完全忘记了 真抱歉
We had just opened the restaurant.
那时餐厅刚开幕
It was for a regular's friend, who made the magazine as a hobby.
常来光顾的朋友 兴趣是写稿 坚持要访问我
So you obliged?
所以你才答应吗？
But it was only about ten minutes.
我们也只是闲聊了大概十分钟
They took one photo and it was over.
然后她用数码相机 拍了张照片就结束了
Did you get more customers after that?
在那之后 店里的客人有增加吗？
Not at all!
完全没有
There were only a few copies. It had no effect.
刊物发行的份数很少 完全没有影响
That's why I forgot. I'm really sorry.
所以我才会忘记 真的很抱歉
The fact that you did an interview is a huge disadvantage.
过去曾经接受过采访的事实 对我们真的很不利
Please don't be like that.
别这么说嘛
A new customer came yesterday, wearing strong perfume,
昨天也有喷了满身香水的新客人
and got so drunk that all my regulars had to leave.
喝醉了大吵大闹 常客全都跑光了
The atmosphere is really bad right now.
再这样下去 店里的气氛真是太糟糕了
So, I'm counting on you.
所以就拜托你了
Watch…
小心…
Wait…
等一下…
I can't do this. Damn it.
我不行了 可恶
Remembering Tanzawa's smug face just…
一想到丹泽的笑脸就…
Don't think about it. Hey!
那就不要去想啊
-That idiot! Hmph! -Oh, hey! Geez.
-笨蛋 -真是的
But it just pops into my head!
他那张脸就是会冒出来 我有什么办法
You know…
那家伙…
he wears leather shoes barefoot.
直接光脚穿皮鞋
Huh?
什么？
I bet he has stinky feet.
脚一定很臭
What's this about?
你到底在说什么？
I'm just insulting him.
只是在说他的坏话
If I don't do this my distressed heart wouldn't heal!
不这么做 无法平复我被逼到绝境的心情
Okay. Did it heal?
平复了吗？
Absolutely not. I need to say 100 more.
完全没有 我还要再说一百个
That's a lot.
太多了吧
Just when it finally stopped doing that…
好不容易最近都没发作了…
Ouch!
痛！
Where's your confidence, Mr. Lawyer?
在说什么丧气话啊 你这位律师
That hurt.
很痛
Yeah, I'm sorry.
对不起
This trial is getting quite a lot of attention. Look.
这次的官司引发了很多讨论 你看
Restaurants that were posted without permission
同样被擅自刊登上去的餐厅
or are suffering from unfair low ratings are beginning to speak up.
或是遭受到不当负评的店家 也开始发声了
Maybe Mr. Tanzawa is being pressured by DotM.
丹泽先生应该是受到了 DotM公司很大的压力
As a company, I'm sure they can't afford to lose.
身为企业 他们不能输了这场官司
So, his smug face you were upset about.
对吧？他那张令你生气的笑脸
If that's a sign of pressure, wouldn't that make you feel better?
也是庞大压力的象征 这样想心情会平复不少吧？
Let's get to work.
开始工作吧
It will be intolerable
要是有很多餐厅跟进 也开始控告我们
if other restaurants follow suit and start suing us to remove more posts.
频繁要求删文 我们可受不了
You must win this case.
一定要打赢
There's no way I'd lose.
我不可能会输给
Not to someone who was fired for incompetence.
无能到被我们事务所开除的家伙
There are plenty of other law firms out there.
法律事务所不只你们这一间
Yes, sir.
是
UMAREPO
（美食报报）
REFILL MASTER
（再来一碗名人）
-Here you are. -Thanks.
-辛苦了 -感谢
-Hi there. -Oh, we didn't order anything.
-你们好 -今天没叫外送啊
I know. Wataro bought a new product and he wanted me to try it out too.
不 棉郎伯父买了新商品 叫我也试用看看
Another exercise equipment?
他又买了健康商品吗？
Come on, go easy on him.
不要念他嘛
It's for your sake too.
他也是为了硝子
He told me that
棉郎伯父跟我说了
he wants to stay healthy and live longer even for a day
难得又再次一起生活
because he's been given the chance to live with you again.
他想要好好养生 活久一点
Alright. Bye.
那我先走了
-See ya. -Bye.
-再见
-Hello. -Hey!
-辛苦了 -是你啊
Hi.
辛苦了
What's wrong? Did something happen?
怎么了？有什么事吗？
Huh? Oh, no. I'm here to see Ishiko.
什么？不 我是来找石子学姐的
So, you haven't given up on her. Huh?
什么 你还没放弃啊？
Um, actually…
不 其实…
We're dating.
我们在交往
-Oh! -Huh?
-啊！ -什么？
Ishiko and I are dating.
我和石子学姐在交往
That's right.
对
That's what speechlessness looks like.
那就是哑口无言吗？
Don't worry and just go. You have a date, right?
别担心 你就去吧 你们要约会吧？
Um…
那个…
if it's okay with you, can I invite Haneo?
你不介意的话 可以找羽男先生一起去吗？
He's treated me many times.
他请我吃过很多次饭
And the restaurant we're going to serves great food.
而且今天要去的是非常好吃的餐厅
-I don't mind. -Really?
-我都可以 -这样吗？
-Um. -Yeah, I heard everything.
-那个… -我全都听到了
-What? -We even made eye contact for a moment.
-什么？ -而且刚刚我们对到眼了吧
I'm not going.
我才不要
Oh, you're not?
你不来吗？
No.
不要
But everything's on me.
全部算我的
That's not the point.
重点不在那里
But the food is really good.
那家餐厅真的很好吃
Thank you for waiting. Here's the Imoni hot pot.
久等了 为您上炖煮芋头锅
Feel free to use Yamagata's spice blend.
这是山形的七味粉和一味粉 可以随喜好自己加
Thank you.
谢谢
It's my treat today.
今天就让我请客吧
I appreciate it.
不好意思 谢谢招待
Are you sure?
不会太勉强吗？
Don't worry.
不用担心
I received an extra bonus.
我领到了临时奖金
-Cheers. -Cheers. Can't lift it.
-干杯 -干杯 太满了 抬不起来
Ooh.
爽
But I guess business is good. Was it an office supply company?
不过现在景气很好吧 你们公司是在卖办公室用品吗？
Yes. They seem to like me.
对 他们好像很喜欢我
That's great.
那真是太好了
Yes.
是
The president took me to Mr. Mikogami's dinner party the other day.
前几天 社长还带我参加 御子神先生的晚宴
-Mikogami as in that Angel investor? -Yes!
-御子神先生是那位天使投资人吗？ -就是他
-Your president is friends with him? -Seems like it.
-你们社长跟他很熟吗？ -好像是
-I see. -Who is this Mikogami person?
-这样啊 -这位御子神是谁啊？
He invests mainly in new companies, regardless of the industry.
他不分行业 主要是投资新创的公司
There.
找到了
Your fingers are in the way.
你的手指挡到了
Sorry.
对不起
Never seen him.
不认识
His online community has 10,000 members.
他的线上沙龙会员有一万人
I've seen him in a documentary too.
我在纪录片里看过他
You really like your documentaries.
你真的很爱看纪录片
But it's cool that they introduced you to such a high-profile person.
太棒了 还把你介绍给这么厉害的人物
They must have high hopes for you.
社长一定对你有很高的期待吧
My family is happy I got into a good workplace too.
我的家人也很高兴我进了一家好公司
I see.
原来如此
I'd like you to meet them.
下次我带你去见他们吧
Yes, sure.
说得也是
Oh! Nothing formal, like for marriage.
不是要谈婚事这么严肃的事情
Yes, I know.
我知道…
They made a big deal when I said I'm dating.
我有我有交往的对象 他们全都大惊小怪
My little brother even cried.
我弟弟不知道为什么还哭了
What?
什么？
You can do it.
加油
-I'm just mixing. -Excuses.
-我只是要沾酱汁 -又在找借口了
So plump.
好有弹性
Yum.
好吃
I'm so glad.
太好了
It has a high rating on Umarepo with four stars.
这家餐厅在《美味报报》上 有四颗星的高评价喔
-Four stars? -Yes.
-四颗星吗？ -对
Wow. You're right.
好厉害 真的
Oh, so it's like this.
这样啊…
Refill Master?
再来一碗名人？
Let me see.
借我看一下
This is…
这是…
-You have a grudge? -It's not like that.
-哪里惹到你了吗？ -不是这样的
You know that I don't want to disclose information.
你知道我不想公开餐厅的信息吧？
Um, could you hold the discussion a little longer?
两位可以等一下再说吗？
I'd like to wait until everyone is here.
我想等大家都到齐了再开始
Everyone?
大家？
They should be here soon.
他们应该快到了
Please take a seat.
这边请
Shall we?
开始吧？
Yes.
好
I'll get straight to the point.
我就单刀直入地说了
You're not Refill Master, are you?
你不是“再来一碗名人”吧？
What are you talking about? I am.
你在说什么？我是啊
To be more accurate, you are Refill Master
精确来说 你是“再来一碗名人”
but you are also not.
却也不是“再来一碗名人”
Please look at this.
请看这些文件
These are reviews written by Refill Master, which we printed out.
这些是“再来一碗名人”写的评论 我把它们都印出来了
I realized something when I was reading them.
我看完之后发现了一件事
Ms. Ishiko.
石子小姐
Yes.
是
Actually, the reviews have different writing styles.
其实 这些文章的写作风格并不一样
This review writes "delicious" in Kanji characters,
像这边的“好吃”是用汉字写的
but this one writes it in Hiragana.
但这里的“好吃”则是用平假名
What I just pointed out is consistent within each article,
“好吃”是用汉字或平假名写的 在同一篇文章里是统一的
but it differs depending on the article.
但是在不同的文章里却会改变写法
And the one that writes "delicious" in Kanji
而在用汉字写“好吃”的文章里
adds the "o" prefix, like in "o-miso" and "o-shoyu."
在味噌和酱油等名词前面 会加上“御”这个美化语
Whereas the one written in hiragana doesn't add a prefix.
而在用平假名写“好吃”的文章里 全都直接写成味噌和酱油
Additionally, in a Yamagata cuisine restaurant's review,
此外 “再来一碗名人” 在评论某家山形餐厅时
Refill Master wrote here that she's from Yamagata.
就是这篇 提到了自己是山形人
But Satsuki, you're not from Yamagata. Are you?
但是沙月小姐 你不是山形人吧？
That's--
那是…
Based on this information,
根据上述信息
we came to the conclusion that there are two Refill Masters.
我们认为“再来一碗名人”有两个人
One of them is Satsuki.
一个人是沙月小姐
And the other person is
另一个人则是
someone who wrote that she's from Yamagata on her social media…
曾在社交媒体上 写出自己是山形人的…
I'm sorry, it's me.
对不起 是我
I wanted to say it.
抢走我的话了
Refill Master is a handle
“再来一碗名人”
that Satsuki and I use to write reviews on restaurants we've been to.
是喜欢四处发掘餐厅的沙月和我 在写评论时的共用笔名
I asked Satsuki to post this.
这次是我拜托沙月贴文的
But why?
为什么要做这种事？
I love Inside and I know you care about it too.
我很喜欢Inside 也知道洋很在乎这家餐厅
He went around visiting farmers
他为了餐厅四处拜访农家
looking for good vegetables and suppliers
想找到好的蔬菜 好的供货商
to support the restaurant.
想要支持这家餐厅
And he passed on that information to Satsuki to let his father know.
他找到的这些信息 都会请沙月转达给爸知道
What? So that was…
什么？这么说…
You figured if the restaurant's reputation spread and sales increased,
你认为只要帮餐厅宣传 让营收增加
Mr. Kayama would admit that Hiroshi's arguments were correct?
就能让香山叔叔认同洋先生的说法 你是这样想的吗？
Yes.
对
I think your food is really delicious too.
我也觉得香山叔的料理真的很美味
I just wanted everyone to know.
想要让大家都知道
But after reading the horrible comments people wrote
但是 看到有人造访之后进不了餐厅
for not being able to get into the restaurant,
就故意张贴恶意的评论
we realized that it's not so simple.
才发现是我们把事情想得太简单了
-I'm really sorry. -Sorry.
-真的很对不起 -对不起
I'll ask DotM to delete my post.
我会请DotM删除我的文章
What do you think, Mr. Kayama?
怎么样 香山先生？
They all just wanted to protect the restaurant.
大家只是想守护Inside
Maybe you'd like to withdraw the lawsuit?
你要不要趁机撤回告诉呢？
I fully understand everyone's feelings.
我了解大家的想法了
I appreciate it.
我很高兴
But I'm sorry.
但是对不起
The store must remain hidden.
秘密店家这一点我不会让步
Why is that?
为什么呢？
Um…
啊…
Dad!
爸！
It didn't work.
失败了啊
It's kind of frustrating watching those two, isn't it?
看着他们父子俩 总让人觉得有点沮丧
Yes?
怎么了？
Nothing.
没事
If the trial is going to continue, we need something else.
如果要继续打官司 就必须想别的办法了
But the fact that Refill Master agreed to delete the post is a big step.
不过“再来一碗名人”同意删文 已经是一大进展了
Whether it's a big step or not depends on how things go, huh?
是不是一大进展 要看接下来的发展吧？
Shall we go?
要上了吗？
Shall we?
要上了？
Oh.
哦
I know we're in the middle of a lawsuit,
虽然诉讼还在进行中
but we came to discuss some matters with you first
不过为了避免无谓的争执
in order to avoid further futile conflicts.
想说双方能不能先讨论一下 所以就来拜访了
I'd also like to settle this quickly. What's this about?
我也想快点解决 你想说什么？
We were able to meet Refill Master, the person who first posted the review.
其实我们见过 最早贴文的“再来一碗名人”了
And she has decided to submit a post-removal request herself.
她本人已经决定 直接向网站要求删文了
I see.
这样啊
Then, I believe Refill Master's post will be removed
那么“再来一碗名人”的个人评论
in accordance with the terms and conditions.
就依照网站的服务条款删除吧
Therefore,
因此
if you could also delete the restaurant information that she--
“再来一碗名人”发表的店家信息 希望也能删除…
I cannot allow that.
这点的话办不到
Based on the terms and conditions, that information has become
那家餐厅的信息 根据网站的服务条款
DotM's property the moment it was posted.
在发表的同时就归DotM所有了
So it's not applicable to an individual post-removal request.
不适用于个人删文的要求
I'll see you in court then.
之后法庭上见了
This is bad. Really bad. Come on, think.
糟糕了…怎么办…快想办法…
Please calm down.
请冷静一点
We might lose this time.
这次说不定要输了
There's no precedent that overturned a case like this.
从过往的判例来看 在这样的情况下 没有任何案子有办法翻盘
-Take a deep breath! -What?
-深呼吸 -什么？
Now, inhale.
吸气
And exhale.
吐气
Good.
很好
Do you have any ideas?
有什么好策略吗？
USHIO
（潮）
UMAREPO LAWSUIT GARNERS ATTENTION
（“美味报报”诉讼案备受关注）
Hello. It's Sadai.
喂 我是定井
Are you sure everything is good?
没问题吧？
Yes, sir. Lawyers usually avoid the word "definitely."
是 律师都会避免提 “绝对”这两个字
But I'll definitely win this case.
不过这次我绝对会赢
SECOND ORAL PROCEEDINGS
（第二次口头答辩期日）
The plaintiff has voluntarily disclosed
原告曾经
the restaurant's information to the public in the past.
自己对外公开店家的信息
Meaning,
换句话说
he himself gave up the business interest that he wanted to protect.
他已经自行放弃 他想要守护的商业利益
Such a contradictory claim by the plaintiff
原告的主张如此自相矛盾
does not deserve legal protection.
不应该受到法律的保护
Hence, we strongly argue that the plaintiff's claim should be dismissed.
基于以上论述 我方强烈主张驳回原告的请求
That'll be all.
我说完了
Well then. Plaintiff and defendant,
那么 原告与被告
can we agree that the arguments are concluded and proceed to the judgment?
答辩就到这里结束 接下来会进行判决 没问题吧？
Your Honor.
审判长
Plaintiff's closing argument is as stated earlier.
原告的最终答辩如同方才所述
However, could you allow me to add a little more to that argument?
不过最后我想再追加一点论述 请问可以吗？
Alright. Go ahead.
可以 请说
I believe…
我认为…
just as there is the right to know,
就像我们有知的权利
there is also the right to be unknown.
我们也应该有“不被知道”的权利
That's how you start. Then…
先以这点切入 然后…
Is it strange to want to keep information private?
不想广为人知是什么奇怪的想法吗？
There are those who don't think it's better to have their information spread.
信息的广传 对某些人来说不见得是好事
There are those who are protected by keeping their information hidden.
有些人因为信息没有被传播 而得以受到保护
What the plaintiff wants to protect…
原告想要保护的…
…are his customers.
就是客人
Inside is only 33 square meters in size and he runs it by himself.
Inside的店面只有10坪大 所有事情全靠一个人张罗
Obviously, the number of customers he can serve is limited.
当然 他能接待的客人数量是有限的
So, he doesn't want too many customers.
所以会希望客人不要增加太多
Because that protects the customers who come to the restaurant.
这样才能保护来店的客人
He wants to look them in the eye, talk to them…
他想要看着客人的脸 和他们交谈
…and serve them food and drinks that they'd enjoy.
端出适合每个人的餐点和酒 让客人开心
He wants to face each customer.
想要好好面对每一位客人
That's the plaintiff's way.
这就是原告的经营风格
Is it wrong…
想要让…
to want to make a customer, who is sitting in front of you, happy?
眼前的客人感到幸福 难道有什么错吗？
I'd like everyone here to think about that question once again.
希望各位能再次思考这个问题
That'll be all.
我说完了
Your Honor. May I speak a few words as well?
审判长 被告方也能说几句话吗？
Go ahead.
请说
That was a lovely speech. However…
你的发言内容非常好
this is a courtroom.
但这里是法院
It's a place to argue the interpretation and application of existing laws.
是以现行法律为依据 争辩法条的诠释与适用性的场所
If you want to make the handling of information, like this one, an issue,
如果在本案中 你想要提出信息处理的问题
that's for legislation.
那就牵涉到立法行为
A job for the Diet, who changes the law.
也就是修订法律 那是国会的工作
If you want to change the law itself, maybe you should talk to politicians.
如果你想要修法 应该去对政治家提出要求才对吧
That'll be all.
我说完了
That was a lot of spectators.
没想到会有这么多人来旁听
I guess many people want to know who'll win this case.
就代表很多人 想要“知道”谁会胜诉吧
It seems so.
是啊
I'll see you at the judgment then.
那就宣判的时候见了
Your sad look was great, Mr. Kayama.
香山先生 你沮丧的样子太棒了
Yeah? But will this really work?
是吗？这样真的没问题吗？
Now, we just wait.
再来只要等就好了
Umarepo is a restaurant guide website managed by DotM
“美味报报” 是由DotM公司经营的美食网站
and is used by people of all ages.
使用者遍布各个年龄层
That website is pretty useful.
这个网站蛮值得参考的
But that "right to be unknown" statement made me think things over.
不过“不被知道的权利”这件事 也让我想了很多
In today's internet society,
现在是网络社会
once information is spread, it remains online forever.
信息一旦传开来 几乎就等于永远留在网络上
My heart aches for the restaurant owner.
想到那位餐厅老板就觉得心痛
You're right. I feel sorry for him too.
就是啊 我也很同情他
I believe we still have a good chance of winning--
胜诉的几率应该还是很高…
For companies like ours, just winning the trial isn't good enough.
像我们这样的企业 不是打赢官司就好
We're being bombarded with complaints.
我们接到了一大堆客诉
I'm sorry.
对不起
Look.
你们看
This, this, and this too.
这个 这个 还有这个
They're all sympathetic to the plaintiff.
都是同情原告的声音
Right.
是
S-So, don't be upset even if you lose the trial.
所以说 即使输了官司 也不要觉得丧气
You came all the way to say that?
你特地跑来就是为了说这件事？
Yes. I was worried about the two of you.
对 我很担心你们两位
Please don't worry.
不用担心
Our goal is to protect the client's interests.
我们的目标是维护委托人的利益
The opponent is a company and they put great importance on public image.
对方是企业 应该很注重公共形象
Therefore, by almost losing the trial,
因此快要输了官司
we thought we could get the public on our side.
才会让舆论站在我们这一边
So, Ishiko approached the press
所以石子小姐找了记者
and asked Satsuki to gather her writer friends
也请沙月小姐找其他撰稿人朋友帮忙
to spread the word about this trial.
把我们奋战的情形传播出去
-That's right. -Is that so?
-没错 -是这样吗？
Which means, that for this trial, we lose to win.
也就是说 这次的官司输了就是赢了
The final touch isn't done yet though.
不过最后的结果还没揭晓
It should be soon.
应该快了吧
Huh?
什么？
-See? -Is it him?
-看吧？ -来了吗？
Here it comes.
来了…
Hello, this is Ushio Law Firm.
您好 这里是潮法律事务所
I'm Tanzawa from the Law Office of Rick &amp; Benjamin.
我是瑞克班杰明法律事务所的丹泽
Oh, thank you very much for calling.
一直以来受您关照了
Haneoka, is it? Please hold.
您要找羽根冈是吧？请稍等
Yes, this is Haneoka. How may I help you?
电话换人接了 我是羽根冈 有什么事吗？
Um…
嗯…
I've already told the court, but…
我已经跟法院说了…
Yes, what is it?
什么事？
After some discussion,
DotM在经过讨论之后决定
DotM has decided to remove all information on Inside from Umarepo
在判决结果出来之前 会把所有关于Inside的信息
before the verdict is delivered.
从“美味报报”网站上删除
Therefore, could you withdraw the compensation claim
所以可以在不要求赔偿的情况下
and the lawsuit as well?
请贵方撤回告诉吗？
Very well.
我知道了
My client's biggest wish is the removal of the information
委托人最大的要求就是删除信息
and we've confirmed he's willing to give up the compensation.
我们已经确认过他愿意放弃求偿
So, we'll accept your offer.
因此我方接受你的要求
Thank you very much.
谢谢
Goodbye then.
那我挂电话了
Mr. Tanzawa.
丹泽律师
Let's meet again in court.
下次在法庭上见吧
Things will be different the next time.
下次可不会这样了
Bring it o--
正合我意…
Yeah!
好啊
Geez.
真是的
Yes!
太棒了！
He's back.
恢复正常了
Hey, welcome.
嘿 欢迎
Why did you call us here?
找我们想说什么？
-Here. -Thank you.
-给你 -谢谢
-Um, could you tell me? -Huh? Tell you what?
-请问 可以跟我说吗？ -什么事？
Why the restaurant must be hidden.
坚持秘密店家的理由
Right.
是
Mr. Kayama told me to ask you if I really wanted to know.
香山先生说 如果很想知道的话 就来问棉郎先生
I see.
这样啊
The truth is, it was actually his wife who told him to open that restaurant.
其实呢 当初说要开店的人 是香山老弟的太太
Huh?
什么？
She saw him working himself like a robot at a trading company day after day
当初她看香山老弟在贸易公司 像机器人一样日复一日地工作
and told him to open the restaurant he had always dreamed of.
就建议他 “来开你一直想开的餐厅”吧
A hidden restaurant?
就是秘密店家吗？
That was her idea too.
那也是他太太的建议
Because if the restaurant got too busy, he'd overwork himself again.
因为要是店里太忙 香山老弟又会太过操劳了
So basically, Mr. Kayama
所以香山老弟…
wanted to keep the restaurant that way to protect his wife's wishes.
是为了守护太太的心意 才会坚持这样的经营风格
I see.
这样啊
I see. It was Mom…
是吗？是妈说的…
But I was thinking of accepting reservations for new customers.
不过我在考虑接受新客人的预约
Just three groups per day.
每天限定三组
Like you said,
就像你说的
the restaurant will taper off if I rely on regulars alone.
只靠常客光顾 生意只会越做越小
It's been a while since you ate something here.
你们好久没在这里吃东西了
I came up with a new dish.
我想了新菜色
I want you to try it.
一起帮我试试味道吧
The three of you.
你们一家三口
But after hearing Hiroshi's thoughts, he said he'll change his ways a little.
不过他听了小洋的想法 也说要稍微改变一下经营方式
Oh, really? That's great.
是吗？那真是太好了
Well…
反正呢…
it's not like either of them was wrong to begin with.
无论是哪一边 原本就都没有错嘛
Maybe it's important for both sides to compromise a little.
两边都稍微让步一下 或许才是最重要的
Are you saying that to me?
你是在对我说吗？
Not really.
并没有
But I'm jealous. To be able to talk to your parents like that.
不过我真的很羡慕 亲子之间可以好好沟通
What?
什么？
It's pointless talking to my parents.
像我们家说了也没用
Ooh, drinking it in one go is torture.
一口气喝完有点难受呢
-Yeah. -I'm off.
-确实 -我先走了
-See you.
-再见
-Dad. -Hey.
-爸爸 -嘿
Um…
嗯…
I know it's long overdue, but…
虽然有点迟了 但是…
I put you and your mom through a lot of hardships.
让你妈和你吃了这么多苦
I'm sorry.
真是对不起
From now on, if there's anything you want me to change,
今后 我有什么需要改进的地方
I promise to do everything I can--
一定会尽全力…
No.
不
Out of all the lawyers…
身为律师的爸爸
you are the one that I admire.
一直是我崇拜的对象
Please stay the way you are.
爸爸 就请您保持现在这样吧
I, too…
我也会…
will continue to nag you.
继续对你唠叨的
I bought some Japanese traditional sweets. Let's eat.
我买了和菓子 要吃吗？
Dad.
爸
Have a seat.
你坐吧
I'll get them.
我来就好
About these hidden restaurants that don't even put up a signboard…
有些餐厅主打秘密店家 连招牌都不挂
Their information is being shared on review websites.
但它们的信息 却被人张贴在评论网站上
On one hand, there's freedom of speech.
人们当然有言论自由
That balance is very difficult to…
但另一方面 要维持平衡是很难拿捏的…
I'm guessing it's about time you've done everything you wanted to do.
你想做的事情已经做得差不多了吧
Right?
对吧？
The firm you're at now
你现在待的事务所
is not good enough for you.
并不适合你
I've talked to a different firm for you.
我已经帮你谈定了另一家事务所
Keep next Tuesday afternoon open.
下周二的下午空出时间来吧
D-Dad…
爸…
Mr. Ao Oba?
你是大庭苍生先生吧？
Could you come to the police station regarding the arson last night?
关于昨晚发生的纵火案 要请你跟我们走一趟局里
Oba's been arrested.
大庭先生遭到逮捕了
You started the fire?
你说火是你放的？
I've got nothing to say.
没什么好说的
If only I wasn't a paralegal, right?
要是我不是律师助理就好了
I want to believe he didn't do it too.
我也想要相信不是他做的
Oba killed my husband.
大庭杀了我先生啊
It's hard to collect evidence.
一直找不到证据吧
You're all a bunch of fools!
你们这帮笨蛋！
Did you kill someone?
你杀人了吗？
Subtitle translation by: Aya Kudo
字幕翻译：赤焰